{
  "prepositionquestions": [
    {
      "question": "Choose the correct statement:",
      "answer1": "A) The hooligans broke into the factory.",
      "answer2": "B) The hooligans broke at the factory.",
      "answer3": "C) The hooligans broke in the factory.",
      "answer4": "D) The hooligans broke onto the factory.",
      "correct": "A) The hooligans broke into the factory."
    },
    {
      "question": "Correct the incorrect statement: Why are our trains so late compared along European trains?",
      "answer1": "A) Why are our trains so late compared by European trains?",
      "answer2": "B) Why are our trains so late compared with European trains?",
      "answer3": "C) Why are our trains so late compared on European trains?",
      "answer4": "D) Why are our trains so late compared under European trains?",
      "correct": "B) Why are our trains so late compared with European trains?"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these adjectives takes the preposition with after it?",
      "answer1": "A) Accused",
      "answer2": "B) Drenched",
      "answer3": "C) Absorbed",
      "answer4": "D) Anxious",
      "correct": "A) Accused"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these verbs takes the preposition for after it?",
      "answer1": "A) Mourn",
      "answer2": "B) Beware",
      "answer3": "C) Determine",
      "answer4": "D) Delight",
      "correct": "C) Determine"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank: The boy ______ brown hair stole my book.",
      "answer1": "A) from",
      "answer2": "B) in",
      "answer3": "C) with",
      "answer4": "D) below",
      "correct": "C) with"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these relations is not indicated by prepositions?",
      "answer1": "A) Time",
      "answer2": "B) Age",
      "answer3": "C) Manner",
      "answer4": "D) Place",
      "correct": "B) Age"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank: He lives ______ Bezongbah ______ Nagpur.",
      "answer1": "A) at, in",
      "answer2": "B) at, on",
      "answer3": "C) on, at",
      "answer4": "D) in, at",
      "correct": "D) in, at"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these nouns takes the preposition for after it?",
      "answer1": "A) Alliance",
      "answer2": "B) Bargain",
      "answer3": "C) Experience",
      "answer4": "D) Ambition",
      "correct": "D) Ambition"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these is not a preposition of time and date?",
      "answer1": "A) On",
      "answer2": "B) At",
      "answer3": "C) In",
      "answer4": "D) With",
      "correct": "D) With"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank: Aahna didn't reach her class ______ noon.",
      "answer1": "A) till",
      "answer2": "B) by",
      "answer3": "C) at",
      "answer4": "D) to",
      "correct": "B) by"
    }
  ]
}